## TeHsin, Chen

Phone: +886-910457832 | Email: tehsinchen1112@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/tehsinchen</u> | Work Portfolio: <u>tehsinchen.github.io/portfolio</u>

# **Professional Summary**

Highly motivated and collaborative Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience in signal analysis. Expertise includes deep learning for fully automated systems, machine learning for human activity recognition on smartwatches, and DevOps with cloud platforms.

# **Work Experience**

# **Cyweemotion Group**

Senior Software Engineer

Jan 2024 - Present

- Team management with the manager includes hiring, mentoring, and crossfunctional communication.
- Designed and implemented comprehensive Continuous Integration (CI) processes using GitLab and AWS.
- Led and managed a key solution development project with over 10 team members, focusing on code reviews, problem-solving, and technical guidance.

## **Cyweemotion Group**

Software Engineer

Jul 2021 - Dec 2023

- Led a team of 6 engineers to provide internal cloud solutions using AWS.
- Developed hand-gesture detection algorithms for smartwatches, including finger rubbing and clenching detection.
- Implemented various human activity recognition models for smartwatch.
- Integrated sensor fusion techniques with the Unscented Kalman Filter (UKF) using accelerometer and gyroscope data.

#### Academia Sinica

Research Assistant

Sep 2019 – Jul 2021

- Co-developed the Phantom SDK for Python in collaboration with Vision Research Inc.
- Developed a fully automated system for image segmentation and classification using deep learning techniques.
- Applied signal analysis and image processing on video to reveal the signal of 5nm nano-particles.
- Built an advanced optical system to study gold nanoparticles as small as 5nm using high-resolution cameras.

### **Education**

## **National Cheng Kung University**

Master of Science (MS), Physics

### 2016 - 2018

• GPA: 4.11 / 4.3

Honors: Inducted into The Phi Tau Phi Scholastic Honor Society.

• Focused on precision measurement and theoretical modeling.

### **Skills**

• **Programming Languages**: C/C++, Python

 Expertise: Signal Analysis, Algorithm Architecture, Machine Learning, DevOps/ MLOps

Platforms: AWS, Docker, GitLab CI

Physics: Modeling, Optics

## **Certifications**

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

# Languages

English: Professional Working Proficiency

Mandarin: Native or Bilingual Proficiency